<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://open.law/schemas/library" xmlns:cache="https://open.law/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://open.law/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://open.law/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://open.law/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://open.law/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="City of American Canyon, Cal., 2022-05">
  <num>2022-05</num>
  <heading>AN ORDINANCE OF THE CITY COUNCIL OF THE CITY OF AMERICAN CANYON REPEALING CHAPTERS 16.01 THROUGH 16.09 AND 16.13 OF THE CITY OF AMERICAN CANYON MUNICIPAL CODE AND ALL OTHER CONFLICTING ORDINANCES AND PARTS OF ORDINANCES AND ADOPTING BY REFERENCE THE 2022 EDITIONS OF THE CALIFORNIA CODE OF REGULATIONS TITLE 24 AND RELATED MODEL CODES WITH APPENDICES AND AMENDMENTS AS IDENTIFIED HEREIN THROUGH EXPRESS FINDINGS OF LOCAL NECESSITY</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2023-01-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="ord" url="./adopted/2022-05.pdf" proof="needed">Ord. No. 2022-05</citation>
      <citation type="bb">City of American Canyon, Cal., Ord. No. 2022-05</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <introduced>2022-11-01</introduced>
      <adopted>2022-11-15</adopted>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <recitals>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>WHEREAS,</conjunction>
      <text>in July 2022, the California Building Standards Commission ("Commission") adopted the California Codes as part of the California State Building Standards Code; and</text>
    </recital>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>WHEREAS,</conjunction>
      <text>California Health and Safety Code Section 17958.5 authorizes cities and counties to modify the California State Building Standards Code by adopting more restrictive standards if such entities determine that such standards are reasonably necessary because of local climatic, geological or topographical conditions; and</text>
    </recital>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>WHEREAS,</conjunction>
      <text>the City of American Canyon has reviewed each of the referenced California and model Codes and it has been determined that certain local amendments are necessary to protect the health, safety, and welfare of its residents; and</text>
    </recital>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>WHEREAS,</conjunction>
      <text>Government Code section 50022 et seq., empowers the City to adopt by reference various Codes including the CALIFORNIA BUILDING CODE, 2022 Edition; CALIFORNIA ELECTRICAL CODE, 2022 Edition: the CALIFORNIA MECHANICAL CODE, 2022 Edition; the CALIFORNIA PLUMBING CODE, 2022 Edition; the CALIFORNIA ENERGY CODE, 2022 Edition; the CALIFORNIA HISTORICAL CODE, 2022  Edition; the CALIFORNIA EXISTING BUILDING CODE, 2022 EDITION; the CALIFORNIA GREEN BUILDING CODE, 2022 EDITION; the CALIFORNIA ADMINISTRATIVE CODE, 2022 EDITION; and the INTERNATIONAL PROPERTY MAINTENANCE CODE, 2021 EDITION; INTERNATIONAL SWIMMING POOL AND SPA CODE, 2021 EDITION; and</text>
    </recital>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>WHEREAS,</conjunction>
      <text>pursuant to the Government Code, the City has adopted by reference various provisions of the above referenced California and model Codes, subject to particular additions, amendments and deletions as set forth in the Municipal Code; and</text>
    </recital>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>WHEREAS,</conjunction>
      <text>on November 1, 2022 the City Council conducted a duly noticed public hearing considered all of the written and oral testimony presented at the public meeting in making its decision.</text>
    </recital>
    <recital>
      <conjunction>NOW, THEREFORE</conjunction>
      <text>THE CITY COUNCIL OF THE CITY OF AMERICAN CANYON DOES HEREBY ORDAIN AS FOLLOWS:</text>
    </recital>
  </recitals>
  <section>
    <num>1</num>
    <text>Repeal and Replace Chapters 16.01 through 16.08 of the City of American Canyon Municipal Code.</text>
    <text>
      <ul proof="needed">
        <li>CHAPTER 16.01 GENERAL PROVISIONS;</li>
        <li>CALIFORNIA BUILDING CODE CHAPTER 16.02 CALIFORNIA BUILDING CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.03 CALIFORNIA RESIDENTIAL CODE 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.04 CALIFORNIA ELECTRICAL CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.05 CALIFORNIA MECHANICAL CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.06 CALIFORNIA PLUMBING CODE, 2022; EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.07 CALIFORNIA ENERGY CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.08 CALIFORNIA HISTORICAL CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.09 CALIFORNIA EXISTING BUILDING CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.11 CALIFORNIA GREEN BUILDING STANDARDS CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.16 CALIFORNIA ADMINISTRATIVE CODE, 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>Chapter 16.17 CALIFORNIA REFERENCE STANDARDS CODE; 2022 EDITION;</li>
        <li>CHAPTER 16.18 INTERNATIONAL PROPERTY MAINTENANCE CODE, 2021 EDITION.</li>
      </ul>
    </text>
    <text>AMENDING THOSE UNIFORM CODES AND CALIFORNIA BUILDING STANDARDS AS IDENTIFIED HEREIN THROUGH EXPRESSED FINDINGS OF LOCAL NECESSITY; and all other ordinances or parts of ordinances in conflict herewith are hereby repealed as set forth in Exhibit A, attached herein and incorporated by reference.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Amend the following Chapters: 16.01 General Provisions; and 16.15 Streamlined Residential Rooftop Solar Energy Permit.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>No Change to the following Chapters: 16.10 Uniform Code for the Abatement of Dangerous Buildings; 16.12 Safety Assessment Placards; 16.13 REPAIR AND RECONSTRUCTION CODE; and 16.14 Water Efficient Landscaping.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>The City Council of the City of American Canyon finds and declares that the additions, modifications, and changes made to these codes are necessary for protection of public health, safety, and welfare due to climatic, geological, or topographical conditions.  These amendments are authorized under Health and Safety Code Sections 18941.5 and 17958 and are read as set forth in Exhibit B.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <text>The adoption of the proposed ordinance is not a project that has the potential for causing a significant effect on the environment and therefore is not subject to review under the California Environmental Quality Act (CEQA). In addition, the proposed ordinance amendment is exempt under the definition of Project in Section 15378 (b) (3) in that it concerns general policy and procedure making.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall sign this Ordinance and the City Clerk shall attest thereto and shall within fifteen days of its adoption cause a summary of it to be published in a newspaper and circulated in the City and thereupon and thereafter this Ordinance shall take effect and be in force according to law.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <text>This ordinance is enacted pursuant to and in compliance with Health and Safety Code Section 18941.5 and as expressly permitted in Government Code Section 50022.2. For all codes, the effective date of this Ordinance shall be January 1, 2023.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <text>The City Clerk is hereby directed to file a copy of this ordinance with the California Building Standards Commission of the State of California.</text>
  </section>
  <procedural-data>
    <text>The foregoing Ordinance was introduced at a regular meeting of the City Council of the City of American Canyon, State of California, held on the 1<sup>st</sup> day of November, 2022 by the following vote:</text>
    <text>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>AYES:</th>
          <td>Councilmembers Joseph, Oro, Washington, Vice Mayor Aboudamous, and Mayor Garcia</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>NOES:</th>
          <td>None</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>ABSTAIN:</th>
          <td>None</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>ABSENT:</th>
          <td>None</td>
        </tr>
      </table>     
    </text>
    <text>The foregoing Ordinance was adopted at a regular meeting of the City Council of the City of American Canyon, State of California, held on the 15<sup>th</sup> day of November, 2022, by the following vote:</text>
    <text>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>AYES:</th>
          <td>Councilmembers Joseph, Oro, Washington, Vice Mayor Aboudamous and Mayor Garcia</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>NOES:</th>
          <td>None</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>ABSTAIN:</th>
          <td>None</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>ABSENT:</th>
          <td>None</td>
        </tr>
      </table>     
    </text>
    <text>_____________________________</text>
    <text>Leon Garcia, Mayor</text>
    <text>
      <table class="layout-table">
        <tr>
          <td>ATTEST:</td>
          <td class="text-indent-1">APPROVED AS TO FORM:</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>__________________________</td>
          <td class="text-indent-1">__________________________</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Taresa Geilfuss, CMC, City Clerk</td>
          <td class="text-indent-1">William D. Ross, City Attorney</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </text>
  </procedural-data>
</document>
